MILAN KAKADIYA

LI: https://www.linkedin.com/in/milan-kakadiya-054693114/

M: +91 7405447776

E: milankakadiya29@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A hardworking and technically astute Senior Backend Developer and Engineer with experience working across a range of product-based and SaaS business environments. I bring significant expertise in providing technical advice and quality IT solutions to many customers and organizations. With qualifications including a bachelor's and master's degree in computer sciences, I have a solid technological-focused skillset with significant competencies developed working in programming languages including Laravel, Nodeis, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML5, and Symfony, MySql, Git, Jira, Jquery, JavaScript.

I bring a strong analytical, forward-thinking, and 'can do' approach which cultivates collaborative relationships with stakeholders whose expectations are regularly exceeded. Organized and methodical with excellent attention to detail, I have an exceptional work ethic and possess the capacity to provide best practice services through the adoption of effective project planning skills, while prioritizing competing workloads utilizing initiative and critical thinking skills.

KEY SKILLS

- Industry Expertise –
- Significant experience gained in the capacity of Frontend Developer and Engineer, supported by relevant qualifications, technical skills, proven project delivery, and the ability to confidently lead and problem solve.
- **Analytical & Problem-Solving Skills** Systematic and pragmatic ability to analyze and synthesize information, then select and implement the right programming languages and technical skills to enhance the user experience.
- Collaboration & Stakeholder Management Consistent and thoughtful interpersonal, verbal, and written communication capabilities enable strong internal and external relationship building and stakeholder engagement, with an overarching ability to create and sustain mutually beneficial partnerships.
- **Project Management & Delivery** Confident and experienced in delivering projects adopting an agile approach, I possess extensive knowledge of the development lifecycle of a range of websites and applications.
- Innovation & Continuous Improvement Proactively identifying and implementing improvement and enhancement opportunities. I am committed to a continuous improvement ethos utilizing an innovative approach to implement robust yet responsive technology change programs.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

- Node.js
- Laravel
- GitHub
- Symfony
- MongoDB

- Typescript
- Google Cloud Functions
- Microservices architecture
- Firebase Functions
- MySQL

- Firestore
- Jira
- Jquery
- JavaScript
- Rest API

CAREER SUMMARY

POSITION	ORGANISATION	DATES
Backend Developer	AIS -Aarav Info Solutions Pvt. Ltd.	Oct 2022 to Current
Backend Engineer	Insight Timer	Sep 2020 to Aug 2022
Backend Developer	SNDK Corp	Aug 2019 to Sep 2020
Laravel Developer	Wama Software	June 2017 to July 2019

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Backend Developer, AIS

Oct 2022 to Current

Aarav Info Solutions Pvt. Ltd. is a product-based company. The company has a product called LeadDial for the US. In this project, we are using multi-tenant architecture.

Responsibilities

- Create a new API, and as per requirement create a feature.
- Predominantly worked with programming languages including Laravel, Node.Js, Jquery, JavaScript, Git, ClickUp, Third party API, AWS, and MySql.
- Good Experience in microservice architectures.

Backend Engineer, Insight Timer

Sep 2020 to Aug 2022

Insight Timer is widely regarded as the best-performing app for overcoming sleep, anxiety, and stress-related issues, with over 100K guided meditations led by the best teachers from Australia and the world.

Responsibilities

- Create new API, and Module, provide support to frontend, and pipeline.
- I predominantly worked with programming languages including Nodejs, JavaScript, TypeScript, Gcloud, Firebase, Jira, GitHub, and Firestore.
- Convert video and Audio files to HLS.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and implement scalable and fault-tolerant microservices architectures.
- Developed, tested, and deployed microservices on cloud platforms like Aws and Gcloud.
- Microservices can be developed using Node.js and deployed independently, communicating with each other through RESTful APIs or message queues.

Backend Developer, SNDK Corp

Aug 2019 to Sep 2020

SNDK Corp is a service and product-based company. The company has one online food sell product and other projects are service based.

Responsibilities

• My work is to create new modules and functionality for the project.

MILAN KAKADIYA

- Discuss the feature with the client and deliver that task in the estimated time.
- Planned, developed, and tested new modules and functionality.
- Restful API, fixing existing code and clean code and following standard of coding.

Backend Developer, Wama Software

June 2017 to July 2019

Wama Software is a service and product-based company. The company has one product Classcare and other projects are service based.

Responsibilities

- My role is to add new features and fix bugs in the Classcare product.
- Discuss the feature with the client and deliver that task in the estimated time.
- Planned, developed, and tested new modules and functionality.
- Restful API, fixing existing code and clean code and following standard of coding.

KEY PROJECTS

Title Lead Dial

Environment Language: JavaScript, HTML, RestFul API, Jquery, Microservices architecture

Frameworks & Tools: Laravel, Nodejs, MySql

Title Insight Timer

Environment Language: JavaScript, HTML, RestFul API, Swagger, Typescript, Microservices architecture

Frameworks & Tools: Nodejs, Express, Gcloud, Firestore, Firebase

TitleLaborNet

Environment Language: Nodejs, HTML, CSS, Ajax, JavaScript

Frameworks & Tools: Nodejs, Express

TitleSpikeBot Cloud

Environment Language: Nodejs, HTML, CSS, RestFul API, Swagger

Frameworks & Tools: Nodejs, Express

Title Mydogcare

Environment Language: PHP, Docker, MySQL

Frameworks & Tools: Laravel, RestFul API

TitlePPMHub

Environment Language: Jquery, HTML, CSS, MySQL

Frameworks & Tools: Laravel, Restful API

Title Bella Pizza

Environment Language: Jquery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, MySQL

Frameworks & Tools: Laravel, Stripe

TitleServmatter

Environment Language: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySql

Frameworks & Tools: Symfony, Google JsonLD, Amazon AWS,

MILAN KAKADIYA

Title Classcare

Environment Language: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySql

Frameworks & Tools: Symfony, FullCalendar, JWT, Restful API, Full Calendar

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

2017 Master of Science in Information Technology, Kadi Sarva Vishwavidyalay, Gandhinagar (CPI 8.4)

2015 Bachelor of Computer Application (Computer Science), Veer Narmad South Gujarat University (CGPA 6.77)

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Gujarati

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information above is correct to the best of my knowledge.